Where'd Masaomi go?
その 正臣はどこに
He went on ahead. He said he had something to do.
さっき帰りました
何か用があるって…
The higher the flames rise—
しばらくほうっておけば その火種が くすぶって くすぶって…
We're done, finished!
オレたちはもう終わった フィニッシュ
You only did what you thought was right, didn't you?
自分が正しいと思うことをやったんだろ？
This is from the Dollars' leader, isn't it?
これってダラーズのリーダーっすかね？
And if the Dollars are behind this, then...we'll crush the Dollars.
もしもダラーズがバックにいるってんなら そんときは
ダラーズをつぶす！
This way!
あっちだ！
You go that way! Block off the entrance!
お前らはあっちだ
入り口をふさげ！
Why...?
どうして… どうして 紀田君が…
Why is Kida...?
The girl ran...
少女は走る
...to escape the shadow that was chasing her.
ただ 追いすがる影から逃れるために
She just wanted to know...
彼女は知りたかっただけだ 真実を
...the truth.
What a pain.
ったく めんどくせぇな
Where'd that brat go?
どこ行きやがった？
We won't let her get away.
逃げられやしねぇさ
Why is Kida...?
どうして 紀田君が…
She couldn't feel anything else.
何も感じられない
Why...?
The shock from what she had just seen was
the only thing resonating throughout her body.
自分が見たものに対する衝撃だけが 心の中に響いていた
You must be happy that you're being released sooner than predicted.
よかったわね 思ったより早く退院できて
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます お世話になりました
I really appreciate what you've done for me.
Here.
はい
Thanks.
ありがとう
The Slasher incidents suddenly ceased after
that night, and the city's peace was restored.
斬り裂き魔事件はあの夜以来パタリとやみ
街は平静を取り戻していた
And Sonohara Anri's uneventful everyday
life should have returned to her as well.
園原杏里にとっても 何事もない日常が戻ってくるはずだった
Sonohara!
園原さ～ん！
Great! I made it in time!
よかった 間に合った
I got held up by class committee stuff...
委員会で遅くなっちゃって
Ryugamine...
竜ヶ峰君
I heard you're going to start attending school again tomorrow, so you're okay?
明日から登校するって聞いたけど 大丈夫なの？
Yes, I'm all better now.
はい もう平気です
Oh, I'll take your bags.
あっ 荷物 持つよ
N-No...I'm fine...
あっ いえ 大丈夫です
Let him take them!
持たしてやんなよ！
Mikado ran his heart out so he could hold those bags for you.
それが持ちたくて 帝人君は猛ダッシュしてきたんだからさ
Anri, how much do you think I had to listen to this today?
杏里 こいつ朝から何べんオレに言ったと思う？
"Sonohara's getting discharged today!"
「園原さん 今日 退院だよね！」
"Will she be able to come to school tomorrow?"
「明日 登校して 大丈夫かな？」
"Anri's so erotically cute."
「杏里って エロかわいいよね」
I didn't say that last part!
最後のは言ってない！
Um...thank you for coming to visit me so often, Kida and Ryugamine.
あの… 竜ヶ峰君も 紀田君も 何度もお見舞いに来てくれて ありがとう
It's no big deal...
いや そんな…
By the way, Masaomi, you just came out from the hospital, didn't you?
そういえば 正臣 さっき 病院から出てきたよね？
Ah, yeah...
あっ ああ
I must've just missed her on my way in.
ちょうど 入れ違っちゃってね
Hmm.
Oh yeah, Sonohara.
そうだ
園原さん 休んでた間の授業のノート
Here are my notes for the time you've been absent.
If you're okay with using mine, I'll let you borrow them.
僕のでよかったら 貸すけど
My handwriting's pretty bad, so they might be a bit hard to read, but...
字が汚くて 読みづらいかもしれないけど
If that's okay, feel free to use them.
それでもよければ 使って
Oh, just a second.
ちょっと待ってね…
I know I brought this one today...
Kida seems...somehow different.
紀田君が 何か違う…
She felt vaguely discomforted by him...
少女は少年に漠然とした違和感を感じていた
Ever since he first visited her in the hospital.
少年が初めて病室を訪れたときから
There. That should do it.
はい これで大丈夫
Kida...?
紀田君？
Anri...
杏里 それ どうして…
What...happened?
Um, it's nothing, really.
あの… 大したことないんです
The Slasher kind of...
ちょっと 斬り裂き魔に… なっ！
Oh, but it's really nothing at all.
でも ほんと 全然 大したことないんです
Sorry, something just came up.
ごめ～ん ヤボ用 出来ちゃった
I guess I'll have to let Prince Mikado do the honors of escorting the princess back home.
姫をおうちへ送る役目はプリンス帝人に譲ってあげよう
You won't get another chance like this for a hundred years!
この先１００年 チャンスはないと思え
See you.
じゃあな
Oh... See you tomorrow!
明日ね！
And so, an unknown feeling of insecurity enveloped her.
そうして 得体の知れない不安が 彼女を包む
Don't do anything until I get there!
オレが行くまで そいつらに勝手なまねさせるな いいな！
Got it?!
A lot of people have joined the Yellow Scarves recently, huh?
最近 黄巾賊の人たちがますます増えましたね
That's very true.
They stand out much more than the
Dollars, since you can tell who they are.
That gang had been around for a while,
but it seems like they've changed somehow.
They've changed?
I can't really put my finger on it,
but they're different from how they used to be...
Somehow...
I feel like they've become more violent.
Saika has entered the chat room.
Oh, good evening, Saika.
Good evening.
Welcome.
Good...evening.
Um, I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
You weren't familiar with the Internet before,
so you got a virus and that's how everything happened, right?
You can't help that.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
You're apologizing too much.
By the way, Saika, do you know of a gang called the Yellow Scarves?
ところで 罪歌さん
黄巾賊ってカラーギャング 解ります？
You mean the people who wear yellow cloth around the city?
Yeah, that's them.
There's also another group that's a lot like them called the Dollars.
Due to the Slasher incidents, both of those groups...
その二つの組織がこの前の斬り裂き魔事件のせいで…
...are in pretty dire straights right now.
Um...
What do you mean by that?
Give it a rest, Kanra.
Don't bring up that stuff with someone who doesn't know anything bout it.
No,
you have to know this stuff if you live in Ikebukuro!
The perpetrator in the Slasher case has yet to be caught, right?
こないだの斬り裂き魔事件
結局 犯人 捕まってないじゃないですか
Anyway, both the Yellow Scarves and the Dollars have had their members fall victim to the Slasher.
で 黄巾賊にも ダラーズにも 被害者が出てるんですけどね
Apparently, they both think that the
Slasher is in league with the other gang.
どうも お互いがお互いを犯人だと思ってるっぽいんですよねー
The Dollars don't seem so hung up on that idea...
ダラーズの方はそんなに拘ってないみたいですけど…
They don't know much about each other,
so I'm sure that breeds misunderstandings.
Either way, if neither of them take matters into their own
hands with the Slasher, blood will rain down upon Ikebukuro.
なんにせよ 斬り裂き魔の真犯人が両方の手でリンチにでも遇わないと…
このままいったら 池袋に血の雨が降りますよー
It'll be really scary...
Now that's a real rivalry!
You don't have anything to worry about, Anri.
Those gangs are running amuck of their own accord.
You're not the real perpetrator, so it
doesn't matter if you come forward or not.
Don't be hasty.
The police are really scary now.
They truly are scary.
本当におっかないから…
They really are!
本当に怖いからね…
Especially the traffic cops!
Thank you so much.
Huh?! Oh, right...
えっと… そっか
I'll teach you about private conversations later.
Um, excuse me, but this is it for me today.
Oh, okay.
See you around, Saika.
'Night.
See you.
Saika has left the chat room.
Alright, I guess I'll be logging off, too.
See you later.
See you around.
Setton has left the chat room.
Kanra...
甘楽さん
About the Slasher incidents...
斬り裂き魔の件…
I'll let you know if I find anything out.
なんか分かったら知らせる
At a bargain price, that is.
格安でね
The real perpetrator has to be somewhere in this city.
この街のどこかに真犯人がいるはずです
The sooner he's caught, the sooner the Yellow Scarves and the Dollars can clear up their misunderstandings.
早く捕まってくれれば
黄巾賊とダラーズの間の誤解も 解けると思うんですけど
I wonder if it'll really be that easy.
そう簡単にいくかな
Neither the Yellow Scarves nor the
Dollars are completely cohesive groups.
黄巾賊もダラーズも
一枚岩じゃないからねぇ
There'll be some people who shake down members of the other group in the name of that rivalry.
私利私欲に走って 抗争って名目でカツアゲとかするヤツらも出るだろうし
It'll simply turn into a real conflict if things keep going like this.
このまま進めば 本当の抗争になるだけさ
I won't let that happen.
そんなこと… させませんよ
I wonder...
どうかな？
I don't think you can stop it anymore.
もう 止められないんじゃないかな
And there's nothing you can do about the Yellow Scarves.
黄巾賊の方は 君には止めようがないしね
Even so, I won't let it happen.
それでも… させません
Hmm. I'm looking forward to that.
ふ～ん 楽しみにしてるよ
"I have to do something,"
なんとかしなければ…
thought the girl who houses an ethereal sword inside her body.
身の内にひと振りの妖刀を宿す少女は思う
"I have to do something,"
なんとかしなければ…
thought the girl who'd only seen the world through a picture frame.
額縁を通して 世界を見てきた少女は思う
However...
しかし…
...the boy who'd passed through that window and had visited her world was already restrained...
額縁を越えて 彼女の世界を訪れてくれた少年は
すでに捕らえられていた
...by the heavy yoke of his own past.
自らの過去という 重いくびきに
He could no longer escape.
彼は もう 逃れられない
Hello?
もしもし
I see.
そう 分かった
Got it.
I'll be right there.
そんじゃ すぐ行くわ
Sorry! Something just came up with my friend!
悪い！ 友達がなんか急用あるっつうからさ
Oh, really?
そうなの？
If you want to hate someone, hate my friend to your heart's content!
恨むなら オレの友達を好きなだけ恨んでくれ
Hate doesn't cost anything, and it doesn't cause me any harm!
恨むなら タダだし オレには 被害がない
It's a perfect "two birds with one stone," it's "many wives for one man!"
まさに 一石二鳥 一夫多妻だからな！
"Many wives for one man?"
一夫多妻？
See you tomorrow!
じゃあ また明日な～～！
I wonder if it's really that important?
はぁ… そんなに急ぎの用事なのかな？
Don't you think Kida's been acting strange lately?
紀田君 最近 ちょっと様子がおかしいと思いませんか？
Really?
そうかな 気のせいじゃない？
You're sure it's not all in your head?
Um...sorry.
ごめんなさい 私 ちょっと 用があるので
I have some business to attend to.
See you.
じゃあ
Did you hear that some of the Dollars
were shaken down by the Yellow Scarves?
ゆうべ ダラーズのメンバーが黄巾賊に カツアゲされたんだってな？
Apparently, they were beaten to within an inch of their lives.
ああ～ なんか間一髪で死人が出るとこだったらしいぜ
The Yellow Scarves are the ones saying that the Slasher is part of the Dollars, aren't they?
黄巾賊の方は斬り裂き魔はダラーズの仕業だって 言ってるけどな
The boy who leads the Dollars knew that things couldn't go on like this.
このままではいけない
ダラーズを率いる少年には分かっていた
However, he didn't yet know that he was
being used like a pawn on a chessboard.
しかし 彼はまだ自らも駒の一つとして盤上にいることを知らない
Customers, eat sushi!
お客さ～ん スシ 食いネ～
Sushi is the heart of Japan.
スシは日本の心ネ 演歌ネ～
It's enka!
I wonder if it's true that he does a Cossack dance when you order take-out?
出前取ると コサックダンス踊ってくれるって ほんとっすかね？
Come to think of it, he was on a delivery when he followed those kids last night.
けど ゆうべの子たち
サイモンが出前に出てて ツイてたねぇ
If you swing that rod, I'm going to turn you into sushi.
この棒振り下ろしたら アナタ スシのネタになるネ
Human sushi... Ooh, it hurts and it tastes bad.
人間ズシ
オオ～ 痛いし マズイネ～
Luck sure doesn't last very long.
ツキってのはそうは続かねぇもんだ
Hm?
Man, those clouds look ominous...
ったく イヤな雲行きだぜ
Does anyone know anything about the Dollars or the Yellow Scarves?
誰か黄巾賊とダラーズのことを知っている人はいませんか？ 誰か…
Anyone...?
Our boss is Kida Masaomi.
うちのボスは紀田正臣です
I've seen him with you, mother.
「母さん」と一緒にいるのも見たことがあります
He said he was going to get revenge on your enemy, mother.
「母さん」の… 大事な友達の敵を取るんだと言ってました
That's...
そんな…
Of course she couldn't believe it.
もちろん 彼女には信じられない
However, her children are unable to lie to her.
だが 「子」は「母」である少女にうそをつくことはできない
Where's Kida...?
紀田君は？
He's going to a meeting today.
今日 集会に来ます
Please take me to that meeting.
その集会に案内してください
And so...
そうして…
...she found out everything.
彼女はすべてを知った
Kida is...
紀田君が…
Is it in the back there?
この奥じゃねぇかな？
If she doesn't run...
逃げなければ…
It's easy.
Why is Kida...?
どうして
I'll love everyone.
私がみんなを愛してあげる
紀田君が…
I'll slash open those yellow children and love them, too.
黄色の子供らも
体を斬り裂いて
What will happen to her?
愛してあげる
捕まったら どうなるのだろう？
I'll love them in your stead, since you can't.
人を愛せない あなたの代わりに
愛してあげる
I don't...want to hurt anyone!
誰も傷つけたくない！
The boy would find out that she's a monster.
自分が化け物だと 少年に知られてしまう
She trembled in fear.
少女はその恐怖におののく
It's too narrow.
狭くて無理っすね
I'll go.
オレが行く
Kida?!
紀田君!
Help me!
助けて… 誰か 助けて！
Someone, please help me!
Hey! It's that thing...
おい！ あれ…
And, standing there in the rain...
雨の中にたたずむのは
...was the female dullahan.
デュラハンの女
The only thing the trapped girl could do was ask for help from someone like her who wasn't supposed to exist in this world.
追い詰められた少女に ただ一つできたことは
自分と同じ この世に存在しないはずの者に助けを求めることだけだった
It scaled the wall with her bike!
あいつ バイクで塀を乗り越えてきたんですけど
I can believe that.
あいつなら ありえる
It's going to make a move!
動くぞ
...Are you serious...?
マジかよ…
Celty!
セルティさん！
I'll explain later.
事情はあとでね
We're getting out of here. Hop on the back.
逃げるよ 後ろに乗って
O-Okay!
は… はい！
Th-Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
Hold on tight.
しっかりつかまってて
I've seen you around for a while,
あんた 昔っから見かけてるけどさ
that suit seems a little tight for a guy.
そのライダースーツの線 ちょっと 男にしちゃ 細すぎるとふんでたんだよねぇ
I don't care if you're a guy, but I could
love you just for the suit if you're a girl.
男なら どうでもいいけど
They do say, "love the Buddha, love his clothes."
女なら そのライダースーツだけでも 愛せるよ オレ
尼さん愛せば 袈裟まで愛す
This is the guy who's always with Mikado and Anri...
こいつ いつも帝人や杏里と一緒にいる…
Oh, I see...
なるほど こいつに顔を見られたくないと
She doesn't want him to see her face.
I don't understand the situation, but I'll do it.
事情は分からないが 了解だ
What?
なんだ？
Damn!
くそ～
You monster!
化け物が！
Don't!
よせ！
They knew one of them had to be the legendary headless horseman.
その姿はまさに伝説の首なし騎士
The fragments of information they knew came together in an instant.
彼らの中で 一瞬にして情報の断片が統合される
The intruder wielded a sword like that of the Slasher.
斬り裂き魔のような刃を握った 侵入者
And the black biker had come to save her.
それを助けに来た 黒バイク
There were also rumors that the black biker was part of the Dollars.
そして 黒バイクはダラーズだという噂
They all arrived at the same conclusion:
彼らは一つの結論に至る
the Slasher is part of the Dollars.
斬り裂き魔はダラーズ
The boy didn't know whether or not that conclusion was correct.
少年は自分の結論が正しいのかどうか分からない
But what he did know was that no
matter how much he thought about it,
ただ 確かなことは
彼がどう考えようと
he wouldn't be able to restrain
those who had witnessed this incident.
この事態を体験した仲間たちをもはや制することはできない ということだ
Hey...
なあ デュラハンって 知ってっか？
Do you know about dullahans?
Huh? Umm... No, I don't.
知らないっす
They visit the homes of those who're about to die.
これから死ぬヤツの家を訪れる
They're headless knights who ride headless horses.
首なし馬に乗った 首なしの騎士なんだってよ
Well, I guess they're like the Grim Reaper.
まあ 死神みたいなもんだ
The boy suddenly thought:
少年はふと思う
"Someone amongst us may die..."
自分たちの中で 誰かが死ぬのかもしれない…
Why...do I want to see Saki at a time like this?
どうして こんなときに沙樹に会いたいなんて…
"The blue dynasty is dead."
蒼天已に死す
"The sky has fallen."
空は死んだ
That was the slogan that a certain yellow flag-toting group used in the Annals of the Three Kingdoms.
それは「三国志」の中で 黄巾賊が立ち上がったときの旗印だという
It certainly isn't very blue.
確かに青くない
Well, it's not very yellow, either.
まあ 黄色くもないけどな
Tanaka Taro has entered the chat room.
Kanra has entered the chat room.
Gooood evenin'.
Are you the only one here, Taro?
Kanra has entered the chat room.
Good evening.
It looks like it.
Starting right off with a private conversation, are we?
いきなり内緒モードですか
There's something I wanted to ask you.
ちょっと 聞きたいことがあって
Um, have the Yellow Scarves always been in Ikebukuro?
あの 黄巾賊って ずっと以前から 池袋にいたんですか？
They started up about three years ago.
At first, they were fairly docile.
The boy who leads the Dollars learned about the heated
rivalry between the Blue Squares and the Yellow Scarves.
ダラーズを率いる少年は 黄巾賊とブルースクウェアの忌まわしい抗争を知る
He remained unaware of the fact that his best friend's former girlfriend was a casualty of that conflict...
その生贄となった少女が親友のかつての恋人だとも知らぬまま…
...and that the man who was answering his
questions controlled the mind of that girl,
そして 語って聞かせるその男が
少女の心を支配し
as well as left an incurable wound on his best friend.
親友に対して 癒えぬ傷を刻印したとも知らぬまま…
...So, only the Yellow Scarves survived—
However, the Blue Squares didn't die.
What do you mean?
The leader of the Yellow Scarves got tired of fighting,
and after he left,
they joined the Yellow Scarves.
You mean they merged?
つまり 合併したってことですか？
To put it simply, yes.
I'm sure neither gang—outside of their respective leaders—
cared enough to find out where people came from.
互いの組織に誰がいたかなんて
リーダー格の人間を除けば いちいち調べたりしないだろうからね
After they threw off their blue uniforms,
They'd get the OK just for saying,
"I want to be in the Yellow Scarves."
But what about the leader who quit?
でも それって 辞めたリーダーの人は…
He probably doesn't know...
知らないだろうねぇ
...that the guys who sent his girlfriend to the
hospital are now hanging with his old friends.
自分の恋人を病院送りにした連中が
昔の自分の仲間とつるんでるなんて
You should be careful, too.
Apparently, there are some guys who are in
both the Dollars and the Yellow Scarves.
And if I spread the word that we had no part in this,
then they'll be likely to pass it on to the Yellow Scarves.
だからこそ
僕らがかかわりないってことを ダラーズの中に回せば
その人が黄巾賊に伝えてくれるかもしれません
If it truly isn't the work of the Dollars, that is.
The Dollars don't have any rules, and it's not like you control everyone's actions.
ダラーズに規則はないし
君も全員の行動を管理してるわけじゃない
While you weren't looking...
...some member of the Dollars...
...could have become the Slasher.
In other words, that's the Dollars' system.
つまり それがダラーズのシステムさ
As long as you're planning to come over to this side...
このまま 君が“こっち側”にくるつもりなら…
You'd best be prepared.
I'll take that to heart.
'Morning.
おはよう
'Morning!
Good morning.
おはようございます
What's up? You don't sound too good.
どうしたの？ なんか元気ないみたいだけど
Maybe you haven't fully recovered...?
体調まだよくないんじゃ？
No, that's not it.
ううん そんなことないです
'Morning.
おはよう
Oh, 'morning.
Oh yeah, I just met Kida at the station and he said he's not coming to school today.
さっき 駅前で紀田に会ったんだけど
今日 休むからって
Eh? Why?
どうして？
I don't know. He didn't tell me.
さあ？ 理由は言わなかったけど
I see.
そう…
See you.
じゃあ
Oh... Thanks!
ありがとう
You can't run from the past, Masaomi.
正臣は過去から逃げられないよ
You're worrying about something to do with that past, aren't you?
今 悩んでるのだって 過去に絡んだことなんでしょう？
If you can't run from it, then you should just face it head on and beat it.
逃げられないんなら 戦って 倒しちゃえばいいじゃん
If I could settle everything with your past too, just by fighting it...
お前との過去についても 戦って 清算できるもんなら
I'd love to.
したいけどな
Why can't you?
どうして できないの？
There's no way I could fight you, Saki.
沙樹と戦うなんて できるわけねぇって
He simply wanted a place where he belonged.
ただ 居場所が欲しかった
Every time he talked with his childhood friend about his new home,
新しい街のことを幼なじみの少年に伝える度に
he'd feel uneasy about his existence, which
was draped in hand-me-downs from the city.
街から借り物で着飾っている自分の存在に疑問を持った
He now understood...
今ならば分かる
...that amongst the Yellow Scarves, the place where he belonged...
かつて 黄巾賊という集団の中で 自分の帰るべき場所は
...was with a single person named Mikajima Saki.
三ヶ島沙樹という ただ一人の人間だけだったのだと
And now, his motivation springs from having found a new place with an important friend.
そして 今は新しい居場所となった
大切な友人のために動いている
Man, it's raining again...
ったく また降ってきやがった
Kadota...
門田さん
You went back?
戻ったのか？
Yes.
はい
I'm here, so I have.
ここじゃ なんですから…
Some great person once said, "The world is a construct of the mind."
「世界は虚構だ」って 偉い人が言った
Some great person once said, "The world is a symbol."
「世界は記号だ」って 偉い人が言った
A detestable past is the product of your imagination.
忌まわしい過去は妄想の産物
That reality never existed.
そんな現実 存在しなかった
Isn't that good enough?
それでいいじゃないっすか
Next Time: The Yellow Dynasty Shall Rise.
制作：lastzzz akira 安静の云 アキラ
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs